A Guide to the Roswell B. Perkins papers FA1851
Rockefeller Archive Center
Roswell B. Perkins papers
1954-1993
Rockefeller Archive Center
Perkins, Roswell B.
FA1851
11.59 Cubic Feet 25 containers: 23 legal document boxes, and 2 letter document boxes
Arrangement
As received.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Roswell B. Perkins papers were donated to the RAC by Susan Perkins in 2021.
Scope and Contents
The Roswell B. Perkins papers largely contain political files that were used by Perkins to give counsel to Nelson Rockefeller throughout his campaign for governorship. The files contain information about both Democrat and Republican political parties and their position on major issues of interest. The files contain in-depth analysis of the Republican platform, New York State politics, and the 1960 and 1968 presidential elections. Also included in the collection is correspondence, speeches, press releases, election memorabilia, and books.
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979 -- Political and social views; Politics and government -- United States; Elections New York (State); Elections -- United States
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 1, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 2 - Comments on Draft Republican Party Platform, 1960 July 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 2 - NAR, Nixon Statement, 1960 Republican Platform, 1960 July 23 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 2 - Inconsistencies in the Democratic Platform, 1960 August (Box 1, Folder 5)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 2 - Analysis of the Republican and Democratic Platforms, 1960 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 2 - Suggested NAR Statement, Comparison of Republican and Democratic Platforms, 1960 September 12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 2 - Analysis of 1960 Presidential Campaign, 1960 November 30 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 3 - NAR Briefing Papers, Thursday Night Television Appearance, 1962 January 11 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 3 - Memorandum, Summary of Proposals Contained in Kennedy's State of the Union Message, 1960 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 3 - Position Papers, NAR Meeting with New York Republican Congressional Delegation, 1962 June 27 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 3 - Draft NAR Statement, "Basic Beliefs of Republicans", 1962 July 3 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 3 - Current Positions Notebook, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Scope and Contents
  Note: For revised position papers, see specific issues notebook.
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 3 - Current Positions Cards, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 4 - Background Paper, Summary Analysis of 1963 Presidential Messages, 1963 March 6 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 4 - Rockefeller on the Issues, Summary of NAR Stated Positions, Prepared by Barbara Jones, 1963 September (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 5 - Questions and Answers for U.S. News and World Report, 1963 September 5 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 5 - NAR Interview, U.S. News and World Report (Released), 1963 September 23 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 5 - Summary of NAR Proposals on Foreign Affairs and Defense, 1963 October (Box 3, Folder 21)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 5 - NAR Answers to Questions Presented by Associated Press, 1963 October 15-16 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 5 - NAR Briefing Materials for "Issues and Answers", 1963 October (Box 3, Folder 23)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 5 - Summary Positions Notebook, 1963 December (Box 3, Folder 24)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 6, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 7 - Eisenhower Statement and Comparision with Rockefeller and Goldwater Statements and Record, 1964 May-June (Box 3, Folder 27)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 7 - Draft Republican Platform "Planks", 1964 June 4 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 7 - Draft "Model" Platform, 1964 June 18 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 7 - Evaluation of Goldwater "Blue Book", 1964 June 19 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 7 - Domestic Issues Platform Materials, 1964 June 25 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 7 - Draft "One Page" Planks, Done for Senator Scott, 1964 June 30 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 7 - Possible Insertions and Amendments to Platform, Domestic Issues, 1964 July 1 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 7 - Revised Set of "Moderate" Platform Planks, 1964 July 6 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 7 - NAR Statement before Platform Committee, 1964 July 7 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 7 - NAR Statement, Suggestion for Consideration by the Platform Committee, 1964 July 7 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 7 - "Moderate" Platform Planks Submitted to Platform Committee by Senator Scott and Background Material on Planks, 1964 July 9-10 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- General Materials - Foreign and Domestic, Volume 7 - Minority Views and Amendments Submitted to the Platform Committee by Senator Scott, 1964 July 13 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Agriculture, Volume 33, 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
- Agriculture, Volume 34, 1961-1964 (Box 4, Folder 41-42)
- Civil Rights, Volume 35, 1959-1964 (Box 5, Folder 43-44)
- Civil Rights, Volume 37, 1961-1964 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Economy, Volume 38, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 46-47)
  A. Economy - General
- Economy, Volume 39, 1961-1964 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  A. Economy - General (continued)
- Economy, Volume 40, 1959-1964 (Box 6, Folder 49-50)
  B. Balance of Payments, C. Government Spending, D. Inflation
- Economy, Volume 41, 1959-1964 (Box 6, Folder 51-53)
  E. Labor Management Relations, F. Taxation
- Education, Volume 42, 1959-1964 (Box 7, Folder 54-56)
- Education, Volume 43, 1961-1964 (Box 7, Folder 57-59)
- Federal - State Regulations, Volume 44, 1961-1964 (Box 8, Folder 60-61)
- Health - General, Volume 45, 1959-1964 (Box 8, Folder 62-63)
- Health - General (continued), Volume 46, 1961-1964 (Box 8, Folder 64)
- Health - Medicare, Volume 46, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 65-66)
- Health - Narcotics, Volume 46, 1961-1964 (Box 9, Folder 67)
- State Books, Volume 57, 1959-1964 (Box 9, Folder 68-69)
  California, Delaware, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Vermont, Connecticut, Minnesota.
- State Books, Volume 58, 1961-1964 (Box 10, Folder 70-71)
  Iowa, Massachusetts, Maine, Michigan, Colorado, Georgia, Washington, Wyoming.
- State Books, Volume 59, 1961-1964 (Box 10, Folder 72-73)
  Kansas-Nebraska, Ohio, Wisconsin, District of Columbia (Washington, D.C.), Illinois, West Virginia, Indiana, New Hampshire.
- State Books, Volume 60, 1961-1964 (Box 10, Folder 74-75)
  California, Oregon.
- Goldwater - General, Volume 61 (Box 11, Folder 76-77)
- NAR Calendar, 1958 September-November (Box 11, Folder 78)
- 1958 New York Campaign - Monaghan, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 79)
- New York State Legislation, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 80)
- New York State Legislature, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 81)
- 1958 Campaign "Historical" (Box 12, Folder 82)
- Advertising Recommendations, New York Republican State Committee, 1958 September 9 (Box 12, Folder 83)
- Republican Platform and Campaign, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 84)
- Republican Platform and Campaign - Testimony before Platform Committee, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 85)
- Republican Platform and Campaign - Platform Report, 1960-1962 (Box 12, Folder 86)
- Republican Platform and Campaign - Platform Material, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 87)
- Republican Platform and Campaign - Republican Platforms, 1954-1960 (Box 12, Folder 88)
- Republican Platform and Campaign - Democratic Platforms, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 89)
- Republican Platform and Campaign - Suggested Speech Comparing Platforms, 1960 September 12 (Box 12, Folder 90)
- 1966 Nelson Rockefeller Campaign (Box 13, Folder 91-92)
- 1970 Nelson Rockefeller Campaign (Box 13, Folder 93-94)
- 1972 Nixon Campaign (Box 13, Folder 95-96)
- 1972 Nixon Campaign - Clippings, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 97)
- 1972 Nixon Campaign - Draft Correspondence, 1972 September (Box 13, Folder 98)
- 1972 Nixon Campaign - McGovern Papers (Box 13, Folder 99)
- 1972 Nixon Campaign - Notes (Box 13, Folder 100)
- 1972 Nixon Campaign - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 101)
- 1972 Nixon Campaign - Fact Sheets (Box 14, Folder 102)
- 1972 Nixon Campaign - Factbook (Box 14, Folder 103-104)
- Cut MTA Bonds, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 105)
- Suggested Answers, Michigan GOP Delegation Questions, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 106)
- Politics - NAR Campaign, 1961-1970 (Box 14, Folder 107-108)
- NAR Press Releases, Volume 1, 1959 August 11-1960 January 25 (Box 15, Folder 109-110)
- NAR Press Releases, Volume 2, 1960 March 1-September 30 (Box 15, Folder 111-112)
- NAR Press Releases, Volume 3, 1960 October-1961 May (Box 16, Folder 113-114)
- NAR Press Releases, Volume 4, 1961 September 24-1962 June 28 (Box 16, Folder 115-116)
- NAR Press Releases, Volume 5, 1962 July (Box 16, Folder 117)
- NAR Monthly Speech Index, 1960 February (Box 16, Folder 118)
- Political - NAR Narcotics, 1968-1973 (Box 16, Folder 119-120)
- Woodrow Wilson School Advisory Council, 1966-1970 (Box 17, Folder 121-122)
- Woodrow Wilson School Advisory Council Meeting, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 123)
- Woodrow Wilson School Advisory Council Meeting, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 124)
- Woodrow Wilson School Advisory Council Meeting, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 125)
- Goodell, Charles E., 1970 (Box 17, Folder 126)
- Coordinating Committee, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 127)
- Robert (Bobby) G. Baker Conflict, 1963 October (Box 17, Folder 128)
- Robert (Bobby) G. Baker Conflict, 1963 November (Box 17, Folder 129)
- Robert (Bobby) G. Baker Conflict, 1963 December (Box 18, Folder 130)
- Robert (Bobby) G. Baker Conflict, 1964 January (Box 18, Folder 131)
- Robert (Bobby) G. Baker Conflict, 1964 February (Box 18, Folder 132)
- Robert (Bobby) G. Baker Conflict, 1964 March (Box 18, Folder 133)
- Robert (Bobby) G. Baker Conflict, 1964 April (Box 18, Folder 134)
- Robert (Bobby) G. Baker Conflict, 1964 May (Box 18, Folder 135)
- Robert (Bobby) G. Baker Conflict, 1964 June (Box 18, Folder 136)
- Coordinating Committee, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 137)
- Dartmouth Seminar - Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1992-1993 (Box 19, Folder 138)
- Debevoise and Plimpton Counsel Documents - Rockefeller, 1958-1962 (Box 19, Folder 139)
- Legislative Leaders Meeting Agendas, 1958-1959; 1993 (Box 19, Folder 140)
- Memoranda to Governor Nelson Rockefeller, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 141)
- "Working for Nelson A. Rockefeller: The Period of September 1953 to June 1959" Draft, undated (Box 19, Folder 142)
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Background Material, 1989-1993 (Box 19, Folder 143)
- Major Speech Outline, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 144)
  Topics: government closest to the people, the job crisis (20 million new jobs), education for all Americans, urban America, older Americans and Social Security, conservation and effective use of natural resources, combatting crime, Communism, Cuba, Latin America, the Space Program, Southeast Asia, Vietnam, Malaysian-Indonesian crisis, NATO, trade with Communist Bloc, defense, and United Nations.
- Political Notebook, 1959-1960 (Box 19, Folder 145-146)
  Topics: Republican Convention of 1960, current assignments, Republican National Committee 1959, intelligence summary, polls, state Republican committee, and publicity.
- Rockefeller Panel Report IV: A Decade Later and A Look Ahead, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 147)
- Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. Special Studies Project, 1956-1957 (Box 20, Folder 148-150)
- Don Irwin NAR Biography, undated (Box 21, Folder 151-153)
- Social Security and Welfare, 1958-1962 (Box 21, Folder 154-156, Box 22, Folder 157-158)
- Counsel to the Governor, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 159)
- Personal - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 160-162)
- New York State Constitutional Convention, 1956-1957 (Box 23, Folder 1633)
- Correspondence - Krock, Arthur, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 164)
- Interview Transcript - Roswell Perkins, Hugh Morrow, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 165)
- Correspondence - Richardson, Elliot, 1965-1970 (Box 23, Folder 166)
- Correspondence - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1964-1970 (Box 23, Folder 167)
- State of New York Report to Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller of the Special Task Force to Study Catastrophic Expense Health Insurance, Volume 1, 1960 December (Box 23, Folder 168)
- State of New York Report to Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller of the Special Task Force to Study Catastrophic Expense Health Insurance, Volume 2, 1960 March (Box 23, Folder 169)
- State of New York Report to Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller of the Special Task Force to Study Catastrophic Expense Health Insurance, Volume 3, 1960 March (Box 23, Folder 170)
- State of New York Report to Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller of the Special Task Force to Study Catastrophic Expense Health Insurance, Volume 4, 1960 March (Box 23, Folder 171)
- Memorial Service for Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller, 1979 February 2 (Box 23, Folder 172)
- Restoring Credit and Confidence: A Reform Program for New York State and Its Public Authorities, A Report to the Governor by the New York State Moreland Act Commission on the Ubran Development Corporation and Other State Financing Agencies, 1976 March 31 (Box 23, Folder 173)
- The Mid-Century Challenge to U.S. Foreign Policy: Special Studies Project Report 1, Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 174)
- International Security the Military Aspect: Special Studies Report 2, Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 175)
  Also titled "The Rockefeller Report on the Problems of U.S. Defense," and part of the "America at Mid-Century Series."
- Foreign Economic Policy for the Twentieth Century: Special Studies Project Report 3, Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 176)
  Also titled "The Rockefeller Report on U.S. International Economic Policy," and part of the "America at Mid-Century Series."
- The Challenge to America: Its Economic and Social Aspects: Special Studies Project Report 4, Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 177)
  Also titled "The Rockefeller Report on the U.S. Economy," and part of the "America at Mid-Century Series."
- The Pursuit of Excellence Education and the Future of America: Special Studies Project Report 5, Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 178)
  Also titled "The Rockefeller Report on Education," and part of the "America at Mid-Century Series."
- The Power of the Democratic Idea: Special Studies Project Report 6, Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 179)
  Also titled "The Rockefeller Panel Report on American Democracy," and part of the "America at Mid-Century Series."
- Nelson A. Rockefeller pins (Box 24, Folder 180)
  Two pins, one large pin that reads "as he said, my interest is in doing a good job as Governor of New York" and a small "Rockefeller" pin.
- Prospect for America: The Rockefeller Panel Reports, 1961 (Box 24)
- Memorial Address and Other Tributes in the Congress of the United States on the Life and Contributions of Nelson A. Rockefeller: Ninety-Sixth Congress, First Session, 1979 (Box 24)
- Public Papers of Nelson A. Rockefeller: Fifty-Third Governor of the State of New York, 1959 (Box 25)
- Public Papers of Nelson A. Rockefeller: Fifty-Third Governor of the State of New York, 1972 (Box 25)
- The Future of Federalism, Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1962 (Box 25)